Guide to the Edmund Jack Pecht World War II uniform and related materials, 1942-1945 MS 590
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Edmund Jack Pecht World War II uniform and related materials
1942-1945
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Pecht, Edmund Jack
MS 590
2 Linear Feet 1 box
World War II military uniform items and ephemera from Edmund Jack Pecht, who was inducted into the U.S. Army 1942 and honorably discharged in 1945.
Biographical / Historical
Edmund Jack Pecht was inducted into the U.S. Army on 27 August 1942 and honorably discharged on 27 December 1945, having served in the Medical Corps both in the U.S. and Europe as a Dental Technician, Fifth Grade.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of a full World War II, U.S. Army enlisted uniform, minus boots. In addition there are patriotic cloth banners and a matchbook cover from the Houston Stage Canteen. Photographs were donated electronically and are accessible online at https://scholarship.rice.edu/handle/1911/78768.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift from Edmond L. "Lee" Pecht, September 2011.
Index Terms
Subjects
World War (1939-1945)
Document Types
military uniforms; photographs
- Series I: Uniform items, 207761
  - Uniform overcoat, Khaki, heavy material, full length, with division and grade patches, 207763 (Box 1, Item 1)
  - Shirt, Khaki, long sleeve, 207764 (Box 1, Item 2)
  - Trousers, khaki, wool, long, 207765 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Jacket, khaki, Eisenhower-type, with shoulder patches, Honorable Discharge breast patch, and sleeve service stripes, 207766 (Box 1, Item 4)
  - U.S. Army hat, khaki cover, chin strap, 207767 (Box 1, Item 5)
  - Tie, khaki, cloth, 207768 (Box 1, Item 6)
  - Belt, web, khaki, with metal buckle, 207769 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Pouch, canvas, khaki, possibly for mess gear or canteen, with shoulder strap, 207770 (Box 1, Item 8)
  - Gloves, wool, khaki, 207771 (Box 1, Item 9)
  - Knife, fork, and spoon, stainless steel, 207772 (Box 1, Item 10)
- Series II: Banners and ephemera, 207762
  - Pillow covers, silk cloth, "Mother & Dad," from California, 207773 (Box 1, Item 11)
  - Pillow cover, silk cloth, "Mother & Dad," from Camp Barkeley, Texas, 207774 (Box 1, Item 12)
  - Banner, cloth, patriotic, "I Always Think of Mother", 207775 (Box 1, Item 13)
  - Matchbook cover, "Houston Stage Canteen", 207776 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Series III: Photographs, 207777
  Conditions Governing Access
  These photographs are only available in digital format, as they were donated electronically.
  - Edmund Jack Pecht in London, 1943-11-08, 207778
  - Edmund Jack Pecht in medic gear, ca. 1943-1945, 207779
  - Edmund Jack Pecht in England in garden, circa 1943-1945, 207780
  - Edmund Jack Pecht in Abilene, TX, circa 1942-1943, 207781
  - Edmund Jack Pecht as a young man, circa 1933-1936, 207782